这是二零二四年河北省初中毕业生升学文化课考试。是英语试卷听力部分。听力部分共有五道题，第一题至第四题为选择题，第五题为填空题。做题时，先将答案答在试卷上，在听力测试结束后。再将答案填涂到答题卡上。现在是听力试音时间。
Excuse me, but could you tell me how to get to the cinema?
Which cinema? The capital cinema.
Oh, it's a long way from here.
You'd better take a bus.
Which bus shall I take then?
I think you need to take number seven.
Thanks a lot.
You're welcome. B, and
试音到此结束。第一题：听句子，选出句子中所包含的信息。下面你将听到。五个句子，每个句子读两遍。请你听完句子的第二遍朗读后，从每小题所给出的三个选项中，选出包含所听信息的选项。
Number one. Our school is nice and clean.
Our school is nice and clean.
Number I'll climb hills with David in the park.
I'll climb hills with David in the park.
Number three. The little boy over there looks very strong.
The little boy over there looks very strong.
Number four. Wow, Jim has colored the flower red.
Wow, Jim has colored the flower red.
Number five. Now, class, please practice the dialogue on page 40 in pairs.
Now, class, please practice the dialogue on page 40 in pairs.
第二题：听句子，选出该句的最佳答语。下面你将听到五个句子，每个句子读两遍。请你听完句子的第二遍朗读后，从每小题。所给出的
B, and Number six.
三个选项中，选出该句的最佳答语。
I just made my bed,
Number seven. Excuse me, can I sit here?
Excuse me, can I sit here?
Number eight. Would you like to play tennis with me?
you like to play tennis with me?
Number nine. What's wrong with you, sir?
What's wrong with you, sir?
Number ten. If you want a friend to repeat his question, what would you say?
If you want a to repeat his question, what would you say?
第三题：听对话和问题，选择正确答案。下面你将听到四。组对话和八个问题，每组对话和问题读两遍。请你听完对话和问题的第二遍朗读后，从每小题所给出的三个选项中，选出正确答案。请听第一组对话，回答第十一题。
what you Could I use your computer,
Wait a minute, Henry.
I'm drawing a guitar for my project on it.
Okay, thanks. Could I use your computer, Lily?
Wait a minute, Henry.
I'm drawing a guitar for my project on it.
Okay, thanks. Question number eleven.
What does Henry want to use?
请听第二组对话，回答第十二题。
Can I help you, madam?
Yes, I'm looking for a blouse.
What size are you?
I'm a small size.
Can I help you, madam?
Yes, I'm looking for a blouse.
What size are you?
I'm a small size.
Question number twelve.
Where does the conversation probably take place?
Please Hey, Lucy.
请听第三组对话，回答第十三至十五题。
How was your weekend?
It was good.
Thanks, Mark. I went to my hometown with my parents.
Really? Is it far from your home?
About ten kilometers.
Oh, it's not very far.
How did you go there?
My parents wanted to drive a but I'd like to enjoy more fresh air, so we went by
bike. That's cool.
What did you do there?
We visited my uncle's family, and my uncle cooked a big meal for us.
We talked and laughed over the meal.
Sounds great. Hey, Lucy.
How was your weekend?
It was good.
Thanks, Mark. I went to my hometown with my parents.
Really? Is it far from your home?
About ten kilometers.
Oh, it's not very far.
How did you go there?
My parents wanted to drive a car, but I'd like to enjoy more fresh air, so we went
by bike. That's cool.
What did you do there?
We visited my uncle's family, and my uncle cooked a big meal for us.
We talked and laughed over the meal.
Sounds great. Question number 13.
How far is Lucy's hometown from her home?
Question number 14.
How did Lucy's family go to their hometown?
Question number 15.
What did Lucy's uncle do?
聆听第四组对话，回答第十六至十八题。
What do you want to be when you grow up, Anna?
I don't know, Mr.
Let me help you then.
What do you enjoy doing?
I enjoy fixing things.
Do you often fix things?
Yeah, and my father helps me when he is free.
Actually, he is very good at making things.
So perhaps you could be an engineer.
That's a good idea, but I don't think I'm good enough at math.
Why not talk with your math teacher, Ms.
She may help you with it.
Okay, thanks. I'll ask her for help tomorrow.
What do you want to be when you grow up, Anna?
I don't know, Mr.
Li. Let me help you then.
What do you enjoy doing?
I enjoy fixing things.
Do you often fix things?
Yeah, and my father helps me when he is free.
Actually, he is very good at making things.
So perhaps you could be an engineer.
That's a good idea, but I don't think I'm good enough at math.
Why not talk with your math teacher, Ms.
She may help you with it.
Okay, thanks. I'll ask her for help tomorrow.
number 16. What does Anna enjoy doing?
Question number 17.
What does Mr.
Li advise Anna to be?
Question number 18.
Who will Anna ask for help with her math?
第四题：听短文和问题，选择正确答案。下面你将听到两篇短文和七个问题。每篇短文和问题。读两遍。请你听完短文和问题的第二遍朗读后，根据所听内容，从每小题所给出的
A, B, -21.
三个选项中选出正确答案。请听第一篇短文，回答第十。
Hi, Tony. This is Peter.
I'm calling to tell you about the basketball match.
We are going to watch it on Saturday, but it isn't in the dream hall this time.
It is in the people's park.
You know, it's near the city square.
Please come to my house at half past two in the afternoon.
Then we can go to the match together.
Is that okay?
Hi, Tony. This is Peter.
I'm calling to tell you about the basketball match.
We are going to watch it on Saturday, but it isn't in the dream hall this time.
It is in the people's park.
You know, it's near the city square.
Please come to my house at half past two in the afternoon.
Then we can go to the match together.
Is that okay?
Question number 19.
What are Peter and Tony going to do?
Question number 20.
Where is the basketball match?
Question number 21.
What time should Tony get to Peter's house?
请听第二篇短文，回答第二十二至二十五题。
Good evening, everyone.
Here is the Chinese music festival of New Star International School.
Let's welcome the first group of singers.
They are four students from different countries.
They will sing a song named
This is Bob from the UK.
He likes Chinese food very much.
This girl is Cindy, and she's from Canada.
Cindy can sing more than 20 Chinese songs.
This is Jack from Australia.
He has traveled to many cities in China.
And here's Linda.
She's from France.
She's doing research on Chinese history.
Now, let's enjoy their performance.
Good evening, everyone.
Here's the Chinese music festival of New Star International School.
Let's welcome the first group of singers.
They are four students from different countries.
They will sing a song named
茉莉花."
This is Bob from the UK.
He likes Chinese food very much.
This girl is Cindy,
and she's from Canada.
Cindy can sing more than 20 Chinese songs.
This is Jack from Australia.
He has traveled to many cities in China.
And here's Linda.
She's from France.
She's doing research on Chinese history.
Now, let's enjoy their performance.
number 22. What will the first group do?
What will the first group do?
Question number 23.
Where is Cindy from?
is Cindy from?
Question number 24.
Who has Who has traveled to many cities in China?
Question number 25.
What is Linda doing research on?
is Linda doing research on?
Question is research on?
第五题，听短文填空。下面你将听到一篇短文，短文读两遍。请你听完短文的第二遍朗读后，根据短文的内容和提示，在信息表中相应的横线上填入所缺信息。
number 28. Question Hello, class.
I'd like to tell you about the food trip tomorrow.
We'll help the farmers pick apples on the hill behind our school.
We can also learn about how to take care of apple trees.
We'll leave school at 9 o in the morning.
So, everybody should arrive 15 minutes earlier.
We'll walk to the hill.
You need to wear sports shoes.
You don't need to bring any tools because our school will get them ready.
Oh, our school will also offer us lunch.
So, you don't need to bring lunch either.
While working, you must follow the farmer's instructions.
Please remember to keep yourself safe.
We'll get back around 3 o 'clock in the afternoon.
Any questions? Hello, class.
I'd like to tell you about the food trip tomorrow.
We'll help the farmers pick apples on the hill behind our school.
We can also learn about how to take care of apple trees.
We'll leave school at 9 o in the morning.
So, everybody should arrive 15 minutes earlier.
We'll walk to the hill.
You need to wear sports shoes.
You don't need to bring any tools because our school will get them ready.
Oh, our school will also offer us lunch.
So, you don't need to bring lunch either.
While working, you must follow the farmer's instructions.
Please remember to keep yourself safe.
We'll get back around 3 o in the afternoon.
Any questions? is the end
听力部分到此结束。
I
预祝同学们取得好成绩。